ruumapp.com 2018-08-20

# Ruum

Protecting the individual's privacy on the Internet is crucial to the future of Internet-based business and the move toward a true Internet economy. SAP has created this privacy statement to demonstrate our firm commitment to the individual's right to privacy. This Privacy Statement outlines our personal information handling practices for this service. Data controller in case of Ruum by SAP is SAP SE, Dietmar-Hopp-Allee 16, 69190 Walldorf (“SAP”), with its data protection officer Mathias Cellarius ([privacy@sap.com](mailto:privacy@sap.com)). This Privacy Statement covers this RUUM BY SAP service and other sites that reference this Privacy Statement. Some SAP entities, programs and/or sites may have their own, possibly different, privacy statements. We encourage you to read the privacy statements of each of the SAP services or program information you visit or review. This Privacy Statement covers this RUUM BY SAP service and other sites that reference this Privacy Statement. Some SAP entities, programs and/or sites may have their own, possibly different, privacy statements. We encourage you to read the privacy statements of each of the SAP services or program information you visit or review. 

### Global Privacy Fundamentals

Our privacy practices reflect current global principles and standards on handling personal information. These principles include notice of data use, choice of data use, data access, data integrity, security, onward transfer, and enforcement/oversight. We abide by the privacy laws in the countries where we do business. 

### Personal Data Collected; Use and Purpose 

The information SAP collects to understand your needs and interests helps SAP deliver a consistent and personalized experience. We will use such information only as described in this Privacy Statement and/or in the way we specify at the time of collection. We will not subsequently change the way your personal data is used without your consent, as required by applicable law. SAP requires your First and Last Name, Email Address and IP Address (“Personal Data”) to fulfill its obligation to deliver the Ruum by SAP service to you, to provide the ability to create personal profile areas and view protected content and to provide customer feedback and support, including communication via email.

SAP and its products, technologies, and services are subject to the export laws of various countries including, without limitation, those of the European Union and its member states, and of the United States of America. You acknowledge that, pursuant to the applicable export laws, trade sanctions, and embargoes issued by these countries, SAP is required to take measures to prevent entities, organizations, and parties listed on government-issued sanctioned-party lists from accessing certain products, technologies, and services through SAP’s services or other delivery channels controlled by SAP. This may include (i) automated checks of any user registration data as set out herein and other information a user provides about his or her identity against applicable sanctioned-party lists; (ii) regular repetition of such checks whenever a sanctioned-party list is updated or when a user updates his or her information; (iii) blocking of access to SAP’s services and systems in case of a potential match; and (iv) contacting a user to confirm his or her identity in case of a potential match.

Additionally, SAP will use the Personal Data for its legitimate purposes to: 

* Tailor information about our products and services to your individual interests. For example, during a visit to our site, it allows us to provide you with specific information on products and services that may be of interest;
* In the case of IP addresses, help diagnose problems, to administer our service, and to gather demographic information. We may also use IP addresses or other information, such as your Ruum by SAP user information you have shared on this service or at any earlier occasion or a campaign code, to determine which pages on our sites are being visited and topics that may be of interest so we can provide you with information about relevant products and services. Generally, SAP will aggregate such data only in an anonymous way and will not tie it to a particular individual unless he or she has given consent. When you visit our site, we recognize only your domain name. SAP will only gather information related to your visit to this service or other SAP Group sites. We do not track or collect personal information from your visits to companies or entities outside the SAP Group of companies. 
* Transfer your Personal Data within SAP’s group of undertakings to the extent necessary for internal administrative purposes;
* Prevent or prosecute criminal activities such as fraud, if required.
* Invite you to participate in questionnaires and surveys. These questionnaires and surveys will be generally designed in a way that they can be answered without any Personal Data. If you nonetheless enter Personal Data in a questionnaire or survey, SAP may use such Personal Data to improve its products and services. 
* Create anonymized data sets, which will then be used to improve SAP’s and its affiliates’ products and services. 

Finally, you consent that SAP may use your Personal Data to keep you up to date on the latest product announcements, software updates, software upgrades, security patches, system enhancements, special offers, events and other information. Any such use of information is based on the consent you grant hereunder. SAP may transfer your personal data to other affiliated companies within the SAP’s group of undertakings for the purpose to inform you about SAP’s latest products, service offers and events in the same way as SAP may hereunder. Any such use of information is based on the consent you grant hereunder.

Any provision of Personal Data is entirely voluntarily for you. However, without this information it will unfortunately not be possible for SAP to deliver the Ruum by SAP services to you.

Ruum by SAP is not directed to users of an age of below 16 years. If you are younger than 16, you may not register with and use Ruum by SAP.

Ruum by SAP is not intended to process special categories of personal data or sensitive personal data. 

### Automated Tools; Analytics

In addition to the information you provide, SAP may also collect information during your visit to an SAP service through automated tools, which include Web beacons, cookies, embedded Web links, and other commonly used information-gathering tools. These tools collect certain standard information that your browser sends to our service such as your browser type and language, access times, and the address of the service from which you arrived at an SAP service. Using these tools, SAP is also able to confirm receipt of e-mails that the recipient consented to receive, and can track other information such as pages visited on the site and whether or not the recipient registers for an event offered by SAP and certain other aggregate data that is not related to a particular individual. 

SAP is in particular currently using the following Automated Tools for the purposes set out below:

Google Analytics. To provide service visitors the ability to prevent their data from being used by Google Analytics, Google has developed the Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on for the Google Analytics JavaScript (ga.js, analytics.js, dc.js) available at <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>. If you want to opt-out, download and install the add-on for your web browser. The Google Analytics opt-out add-on is designed to be compatible with Chrome, Internet Explorer 8-11, Safari, Firefox and Opera. In order to function, the opt-out add-on must be able to load and execute properly on your browser. For Internet Explorer, 3rd-party cookies must be enabled. Learn more about about the opt-out and how to properly install the browser add-on [here](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/181881?hl=en). 

### Retention periods

SAP will only store your Personal Data for the following periods as applicable:

  * for Personal Data required to deliver the Ruum by SAP Service, for as long as it is required to allow you to participate in Ruum by SAP;
  * where SAP’s use of your Personal Data is based on SAP’s legitimate business interest as further stated herein, either until your participation has ended or until you object against such use by SAP; and
  * where the processing of your Personal Data is based on your consent either until your participation has ended or until you revoke your consent granted hereunder;

plus, in each case and where applicable, any additional periods under applicable laws during which SAP has to retain your Personal Data. 

Please direct any such objections to [feedback@ruumapp.com](mailto:feedback@ruumapp.com). Kindly note that in this case the use of certain services or offerings may either be limited or not possible any longer. In case there is a contradicting statutory obligation for SAP to retain your Personal Data, SAP will block it against further processing and then delete the relevant Personal Data when the requirement to retain it has ceased.

### Sharing Your Personal Data

SAP will not send your personal data outside the SAP Group except to the recipients listed below, unless we are otherwise required to do so by applicable laws.

The following categories of recipients may receive personal data:

  * Service Providers, who help SAP provide the Service;
  * Analytics tools providers, as and to the extent described below in “Analytics”
  * Other SAP Group Companies 

### Details of transfers outside the EU

As part of a global group of companies, SAP has affiliates and third-party service providers within as well as outside of the European Economic Area (the “EEA”). As a consequence, whenever SAP is using or otherwise processing your Personal Data for the purposes set out in this Privacy Statement, SAP may transfer your Personal Data to countries outside of the EEA including to such countries in which a statutory level of data protection applies that is not comparable to the level of data protection within the EEA. Whenever such transfer occurs, it is based on the Standard Contractual Clauses (according to EU Commission Decision 87/2010/EC or any future replacement) in order to contractually provide that your Personal Data is subject to a level of data protection that applies within the EEA. You may obtain a redacted copy (from which commercial information and information that is not relevant has been removed) of such Standard Contractual Clauses by sending a request to [privacy@sap.com](mailto:privacy@sap.com).

### Links to Other Sites

This site may contain links to other sites. SAP is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of other services outside the SAP Group of companies. 

### Country-Specific Disclosures

#### United States.

##### California Do Not Track Disclosure

We use cookies to deliver personalized content, to save you having to re-enter your password repeatedly, to keep track of your shopping cart, and to tailor our information offerings to how you and others use the site. Cookies are identifiers that can be sent from a site via your browser to be placed on your computer's hard drive. Thereafter when you visit a site, a message is sent back to the web server by the browser accessing the site. Your browser may allow you to set a “Do not track” preference, which tells sites you visit that you do not want these messages to be submitted. Our site does not honor “Do not track” requests, but you may elect not to accept cookies by changing the designated settings on your web browser. However, not utilizing cookies may prevent you from using certain functions and features of our site. This site does not allow third parties to gather information about you over time and across sites. 

##### Children's Privacy

We do not intend for our services or online services to be used by anyone under the age of 13. If you are a parent or guardian and believe we may have collected information about a child, please contact us as described in this Privacy Statement. 

#### Russia

The below applies to users residing in the Russian Federation:

The services hereunder are not intended for use by the citizens of the Russian Federation, who reside in Russia. If you are a Russian citizen residing in Russia, you are hereby notified, that any Personal Data that you input into the services will be solely at your own risk and responsibility, you explicitly agree that SAP may accumulate your Personal Data and will process this data in the US and in other countries and that you will not hold SAP accountable for any potential non-observance of the Russian Federation legislation. 

### Inquiries, Access and Updating Your Personal Data

SAP needs your help in keeping the personal data you have shared with us accurate and up to date. If you are a registered user, you may make these updates yourself online under “My Account”. You may also make these updates or other changes by sending an email to [feedback@ruumapp.com](mailto:feedback@ruumapp.com).

You can request from SAP at any time information about which Personal Data SAP processes about you and the correction or deletion of such Personal Data. Please note, however, that SAP can or will delete your Personal Data only if there is no statutory obligation or prevailing right of SAP to retain it. Kindly note further that if you request that SAP deletes your Personal Data, you will not be able to continue to use any SAP service that requires SAP’s use of your Personal Data.

You may withdraw your consent for SAP to process Personal Data as stated herein at any time. Once you assert this right, SAP will not process your Personal Data any longer unless legally required to do so. However, any withdrawal has no effect on past processing by SAP up to the point in time of your withdrawal. Please direct any such request to [feedback@ruumapp.com](mailto:feedback@ruumapp.com).

Furthermore, you can request from SAP that SAP restricts your Personal Data from any further processing in any of the following events: (i) you state that the Personal Data SAP has about you is incorrect, (but only for as long as SAP requires to check the accuracy of the relevant Personal Data), (ii) there is no legal basis for SAP processing your Personal Data and you demand that SAP restricts your Personal Data from further processing, or (iii) SAP no longer requires your Personal Data but you claim that you require SAP to retain such data in order to claim or exercise legal rights or to defend against third party claims or (iv) in case you object to the processing of your Personal Data by SAP (based on SAP’s legitimate interest as further set out in Section B. below) for as long as it is required to review as to whether SAP has a prevailing interest or legal obligation in processing your Personal Data.

If you take the view that SAP is not processing Personal Data in accordance with the requirements set out herein or applicable EEA data protection laws, you can at any time lodge a complaint with the data protection authority of the EEA country where you live or with the data protection authority of the country or state where SAP has its registered seat

If you have any other questions about this privacy statement or if you wish to inspect the information we hold about you, please contact [feedback@ruumapp.com](mailto:feedback@ruumapp.com).

Updated: February 28, 2018
